A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, projects, RG 1.3 FA388
Rockefeller Archive Center
- American Cultural Heritage, 1936, 1960-1984; 270; 22 Box(es)
  While some projects, like the Atlantic Studies Center at Johns Hopkins University, received major funding and some grants went to well-established scholars and institutions, the foundation's concern to cast its grants widely is striking. In assessing a grant to collect a history of the Gros Ventre tribe, for example, the foundation officer noted that while they could look for someone with "fancier credentials," they might also give "direct and substantial encouragement" to this "diligent amateur." The foundation also was concerned, in redressing the historical record, that the story be told by those who had lived it. The focus on oral history reflects this interest, but the concern was really a broader one to empower minorities to interpret their own heritage. Officers carefully considered a scholar's rapport with the community under study and gave extra weight to a shared regional or ethnic background. They favored one proposal, for example, because it presented the "possibility of furthering Southern Studies by people from this region, in this region." Some grants trained individuals in techniques that could then be brought back to the community.
  The smallest grant - for $615 - allowed a scholar to complete a study of the black poet and novelist Jean Toomer. As the final grant report noted, people were impressed that "of all the RF's worldwide activities,... we could still take time to make such a small grant for such an obscure project."
  While the American Cultural Heritage Program was a limited initiative, it is interesting to see the ways it intersected with and helped shape new initiatives in historical study. It encouraged interdisciplinary and particularly anthropological approaches to historical questions, supported the study of folklore, family history, religion, labor history, women's studies, community and regional studies, and embraced the application of new media to the presentation of traditional subjects. That these approaches are commonplace in textbooks today attests in some measure to the program's success. Researchers may also find in these files reflections of present-day concerns with cultural identity, heritage, and meaning.
  - American Cultural Heritage - Minutes, 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Cultural Heritage, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Cultural Heritage, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Cultural Heritage, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Cultural Heritage - Supplementary Material, 1964, 1966, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alice Lloyd College - Appalachian Oral History, 1973-1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alice Lloyd College - Appalachian Oral History - Evaluation, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alice Lloyd College - Appalachian Oral History - Supplementary Material (I), 1973, 1975; Folder 1 of 5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Alice Lloyd College - Appalachian Oral History - Supplementary Material (II), 1973-1977; Folder 2 of 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alice Lloyd College - Appalachian Oral History - Supplementary Material (III), 1975-1976; Folder 3 of 5 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alice Lloyd College - Appalachian Oral History - Supplementary Material (IV), 1978-1979; Folder 4 of 5 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Alice Lloyd College - Appalachian Oral History - Supplementary Material (V), 1976; Folder 5 of 5 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - American National Theatre and Academy - "Promised Land" Television Series, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - American National Theatre and Academy - "Promised Land" Television Series, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - American National Theatre and Academy - "Promised Land" Television Series, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - American National Theatre and Academy - "Promised Land" Television Series - Evaluation, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - American Universities Field Staff - Morgan, Lael, 1971-May 1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - American Universities Field Staff - Morgan, Lael, June 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Arizona State University - Southwest Labor Studies Conference, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Arizona State University - Southwest Labor Studies Conference - Evaluation, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Arkansas College - Folklore Education Consortium, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Arkansas College - Folklore Education Consortium, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Arkansas College - Folklore Education Consortium, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Arkansas College - Folklore Education Consortium, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Arkansas College - Folklore Education Consortium - Evaluation, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Arkansas College - Folklore Education Consortium - Supplementary Material (I), 1975; Folder 1 of 5 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Arkansas College - Folklore Education Consortium - Supplementary Material (II), 1976-1979; Folder 2 of 5 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Arkansas College - Folklore Education Consortium - Supplementary Material (III), 1979-1980; Folder 3 of 5 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Arkansas College - Folklore Education Consortium - Supplementary Material (IV), 1980; Folder 4 of 5 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Arkansas College - Folklore Education Consortium - Supplementary Material (V), 1980; Folder 5 of 5 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Bramdeis University - Fuchs, Lawrence H., 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - California Historical Society - Farm Photograph Exhibit (I), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - California Historical Society - Farm Photograph Exhibit (II), 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - California Historical Society - Farm Photograph Exhibit (II), 1975-1977, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Clark University - Family History Project, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Clark University - Family History Project, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Clark University - Family History Project, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Clark University - Family History Project, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Clark University - Family History Project, 1977-1980 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Clark University - Family History Project - Supplementary Material (I), 1969; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Clark University - Family History Project - Supplementary Material (II), 1970-1971, 1978; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Clark University - Family History Project - Supplementary Material (III), 1971-1974; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Columbia University - Luening, Otto, 1972-1980 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Columbia University - Luening, Otto - Supplementary Material (I), 1973; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Columbia University - Luening, Otto - Supplementary Material (II), 1973; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Concord College - Rogers, F. Scott, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Consumers Union Foundation, Inc. - Consumer Movement Center - Grant Actions, 1977-1980 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Consumers Union Foundation, Inc. - Consumer Movement Center, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Consumers Union Foundation, Inc. - Consumer Movement Center, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Consumers Union Foundation, Inc. - Consumer Movement Center, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Consumers Union Foundation, Inc. - Consumer Movement Center, 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Consumers Union Foundation, Inc. - Consumer Movement Center - Evaluation, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Consumers Union Foundation, Inc. - Consumer Movement Center - Supplementary Material (I), 1979-1981; Folder 1 of 4 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Consumers Union Foundation, Inc. - Consumer Movement Center - Supplementary Material (II), 1981; Folder 2 of 4 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Consumers Union Foundation, Inc. - Consumer Movement Center - Supplementary Material (III), 1960-1975; Folder 3 of 4 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Consumers Union Foundation, Inc. - Consumer Movement Center - Supplementary Material (IV), 1936, 1971-1976; Folder 4 of 4 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Cornell University - Lafayette's Papers, 1975-1979 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Cornell University - Lafayette's Papers - Evaluation, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Cornell University - Lafayette's Papers - Supplementary Material, 1976-1979 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Douglass Museum of African Art - Community Outreach, 1975-1981 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Douglass Museum of African Art - Community Outreach - Supplemental Material (I), 1972-1978; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Douglass Museum of African Art - Community Outreach - Supplemental Material (II), 1972-1978; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Duke University - Walker, Eugene P., 1971-1973 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Florida State University - Dorothy Day Oral History, 1974-1977, 1979, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - George Mason University - Federal Theatre Project, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - George Mason University - Federal Theatre Project, 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - George Mason University - Federal Theatre Project - Evaluation, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Georgia State University - Southern Labor History Conference, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Georgia State University - Southern Labor History Conference, 1978-1982 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Georgia State University - Southern Labor History Conference - Evaluation, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Halsted, James A., 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Halsted, James A., 1977-1979, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Halsted, James A. - Evaluation, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Higgins, Chester, 1973-1974, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Higgins, Chester - Supplementary Material, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Indiana University - Wiggins, William H., 1971-May 1972 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Indiana University - Wiggins, William H., June 1972-1974 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Institute for Advanced Study - Maxwell, Kenneth R., 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Institute for Advanced Study - Maxwell, Kenneth R., 1973-1975 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Institute for Advanced Study - Maxwell, Kenneth R. - Supplementary Material, 1971-1974 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Jackson State College - Folklore Films, 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Jackson State College - Folklore Films - Supplementary Material, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Johns Hopkins University - Atlantic Studies, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Johns Hopkins University - Atlantic Studies, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Johns Hopkins University - Atlantic Studies, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Johns Hopkins University - Atlantic Studies, 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Johns Hopkins University - Atlantic Studies, 1978-1981 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Johns Hopkins University - Atlantic Studies - Evaluation, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 88)
  - Learning Design Associates, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - Learning Design Associates, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - Learning Design Associates - Evaulation, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 91)
  - Learning Design Associates - Supplementary Material (I), 1974; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 11, Folder 92)
  - Learning Design Associates - Supplementary Material (II), 1974; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - Learning Design Associates - Supplementary Material (III), 1976; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - Lewis and Clark College - American History Theatre Project, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - Lewis and Clark College - American History Theatre Project - Supplementary Material, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Marquette University - Dorothy Day Oral History, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - Marquette University - Dorothy Day Oral History - Evaluation, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 98)
  - Michigan State University - Korth, Philip A., 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 99)
  - Michigan State University - Korth, Philip A., 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 100)
  - New School - Morgenthau, Hans J., 1970-1975 (Box 12, Folder 101)
  - Occidental College - Hewitt, Mary Jane, 1975-1979 (Box 12, Folder 102)
  - Occidental College - Hewitt, Mary Jane - Evaluation, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 103)
  - Oregon Historical Society - Chen, Chia-lin (I), 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 104)
  - Oregon Historical Society - Chen, Chia-lin (II), 1972-1975 (Box 12, Folder 105)
  - Pasanella, Ann K., 1975-1980 (Box 12, Folder 106)
  - Pasanella, Ann K. - Evaluation, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - Patterson Foundation - Jacoby, Susan, 1973-1975, 1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 108)
  - Patterson Foundation - Jacoby, Susan - Evaluation, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 109)
  - Patterson Foundation - Jacoby, Susan - Supplementary Material, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 110)
  - Pennsylvania State University - Religion and American Culture, 1969-1974 (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - Pennsylvania State University - Tourism and Folk Culture, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 112)
  - Pennsylvania State University - Tourism and Folk Culture, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 113)
  - Pennsylvania State University - Tourism and Folk Culture, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 114)
  - Pennsylvania State University - Tourism and Folk Culture, April 1978 (Box 13, Folder 115)
  - Pennsylvania State University - Tourism and Folk Culture, June-December 1978 (Box 13, Folder 116)
  - Pennsylvania State University - Tourism and Folk Culture, 1979-1981 (Box 13, Folder 117)
  - Pennsylvania State University - Tourism and Folk Culture - Evaluation, 1981-1983 (Box 14, Folder 118)
  - Pitlick, Mary L. (I), 1974-1978 (Box 14, Folder 119)
  - Pitlick, Mary L. (II), 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 120)
  - Pitlick, Mary L. (III), 1974-1979 (Box 14, Folder 121)
  - Pitlick, Mary L. - Evaluation, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 122)
  - Radcliffe College - Parker, Gail Thain, 1971-1974, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 123)
  - South East Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Studies Center - Tri-City Multi-Media Project, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 124)
  - South East Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Studies Center - Tri-City Multi-Media Project, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 125)
  - South East Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Studies Center - Tri-City Multi-Media Project, 1976, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 126)
  - South East Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Studies Center - Tri-City Multi-Media Project - Evaluation, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 127)
  - South East Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Studies Center - Tri-City Multi-Media Project - Supplementary Material, 1974-1975 (Box 14, Folder 128)
  - South East Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Studies Center - Wrobel, Paul, February-April 1973 (Box 14, Folder 129)
  - South East Michigan Regional Ethnic Heritage Studies Center - Wrobel, Paul, May 1973-1975 (Box 15, Folder 130)
  - Sun Valley Center for the Arts and Humanities - Institute of the American West, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 131)
  - Sun Valley Center for the Arts and Humanities - Institute of the American West, 1977-1978, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 132)
  - Sun Valley Center for the Arts and Humanities - Institute of the American West - Evaluation, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 133)
  - Union Theological Seminary - Cone, James H., 1973 (Box 15, Folder 134)
  - Union Theological Seminary - Cone, James H., 1974-1975 (Box 15, Folder 135)
  - Union Theological Seminary - Cone, James H. - Supplementary Material (I), 1974-1975; Folder 1 of 4 (Box 15, Folder 136)
  - Union Theological Seminary - Cone, James H. - Supplementary Material (II), 1974; Folder 2 of 4 (Box 15, Folder 137)
  - Union Theological Seminary - Cone, James H. - Supplementary Material (III), 1974; Folder 3 of 4 (Box 15, Folder 138)
  - Union Theological Seminary - Cone, James H. - Supplementary Material (IV), 1974; Folder 4 of 4 (Box 15, Folder 139)
  - University of Arizona - Browder, Robert P., 1975-1980 (Box 16, Folder 140)
  - University of Arizona - Browder, Robert P. - Evaluation, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 141)
  - University of Arizona - Underhill, Lonnie E., 1972-January 1973 (Box 16, Folder 142)
  - University of Arizona - Underhill, Lonnie E., February 1973-1974, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 143)
  - University of Arizona - Underhill, Lonnie E. - Supplementary Material, 1974, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 144)
  - University of California - Capture, George P., 1972-1974 (Box 16, Folder 145)
  - University of Hawaii - Asian-American Studies, 1971-1977 (Box 16, Folder 146)
  - University of Hawaii - Asian-American Studies - Supplementary Material (I), 1971-1975; Folder 1 of 5 (Box 16, Folder 147)
  - University of Hawaii - Asian-American Studies - Supplementary Material (II), 1971; Folder 2 of 5 (Box 16, Folder 148)
  - University of Hawaii - Asian-American Studies - Supplementary Material (III), 1973; Folder 3 of 5 (Box 17, Folder 149)
  - University of Hawaii - Asian-American Studies - Supplementary Material (IV), 1974; Folder 4 of 5 (Box 17, Folder 150)
  - University of Hawaii - Asian-American Studies - Supplementary Material (V), 1975; Folder 5 of 5 (Box 17, Folder 151)
  - University of Iowa - Film and American Civilization, 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 152)
  - University of Iowa - Film and American Civilization, January 1972 (Box 17, Folder 153)
  - University of Iowa - Film and American Civilization, February 1972-1976 (Box 17, Folder 154)
  - University of Iowa - Turner, Darwin T., 1971-1974, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 155)
  - University of Kentucky - Appalachian Studies, 1975-July 1976 (Box 17, Folder 156)
  - University of Kentucky - Appalachian Studies, August-December 1976 (Box 18, Folder 157)
  - University of Kentucky - Appalachian Studies, January 1977 (Box 18, Folder 158)
  - University of Kentucky - Appalachian Studies, February-September 1977 (Box 18, Folder 159)
  - University of Kentucky - Appalachian Studies, 1978-1980 (Box 18, Folder 160)
  - University of Kentucky - Appalachian Studies - Evaluation, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 161)
  - University of Missouri - Hartmann, Susan M., 1972-1975, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 162)
  - University of North Carolina - Southern Oral History (I), 1974-1976 (Box 18, Folder 163)
  - University of North Carolina - Southern Oral History (II), 1973-1974 (Box 18, Folder 164)
  - University of North Carolina - Southern Oral History (III), 1975-1976, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 165)
  - University of Pennsylvania - Frankford Community Project, August-October 1976 (Box 18, Folder 166)
  - University of Pennsylvania - Frankford Community Project, December 1976-1978, 1980-1982 (Box 19, Folder 167)
  - University of Pennsylvania - Frankford Community Project - Evaluation, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 168)
  - University of Southwestern Louisiana - Acadian and Creole Studies, September 1976 (Box 19, Folder 169)
  - University of Southwestern Louisiana - Acadian and Creole Studies, October 1976-1977 (Box 19, Folder 170)
  - University of Southwestern Louisiana - Acadian and Creole Studies, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 171)
  - University of Southwestern Louisiana - Acadian and Creole Studies, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 172)
  - University of Southwestern Louisiana - Acadian and Creole Studies - Evaluation, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 173)
  - University of Southwestern Louisiana - Acadian and Creole Studies - Supplementary Material, 1976, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 174)
  - University of Texas - Photographic and Oral History Project, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 175)
  - University of Texas - Photographic and Oral History Project, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 176)
  - University of Texas - Photographic and Oral History Project, 1977-1979 (Box 20, Folder 177)
  - University of Texas - Photographic and Oral History Project - Evaluation, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 178)
  - University of Texas - Photographic and Oral History Project - Supplementary Material, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 179)
  - University of Wisconsin - History of the Serbs, 1974-1979 (Box 20, Folder 180)
  - University of Wisconsin - History of the Serbs - Evaluation, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 181)
  - WGBH Educational Foundation - Amoskeag Manufacturing Company Documentary, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 182)
  - WGBH Educational Foundation - Amoskeag Manufacturing Company Documentary, 1977-1980, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 183)
  - WGBH Educational Foundation - Amoskeag Manufacturing Company Documentary - Evaluation, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 184)
  - WGBH Educational Foundation - Amoskeag Manufacturing Company Documentary - Supplementary Material, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 185)
  - Whisnant, David (I), 1974-1975 1978 (Box 21, Folder 186)
  - Whisnant, David (II), 1973-1977 (Box 21, Folder 187)
  - Whisnant, David - Supplementary Material (I), 1973; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 21, Folder 188)
  - Whisnant, David - Supplementary Material (II), 1973; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 21, Folder 189)
  - Whisnant, David - Supplementary Material (III), 1973; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 21, Folder 190)
  - Wisconsin Academy of Sciences, Arts and Letters - David H. Stevens Oral History, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 191)
  - Wisconsin Academy of Sciences, Arts and Letters - David H. Stevens Oral History, 1976-1977 (Box 21, Folder 192)
  - Wisconsin Academy of Sciences, Arts and Letters - David H. Stevens Oral History - Evaluation, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 193)
  - Wisconsin Academy of Sciences, Arts and Letters - David H. Stevens Oral History - Supplementary Material (I), 1975-1976; Folder 1 of 4 (Box 21, Folder 194)
  - Wisconsin Academy of Sciences, Arts and Letters - David H. Stevens Oral History - Supplementary Material (II), 1975; Folder 2 of 4 (Box 21, Folder 195)
  - Wisconsin Academy of Sciences, Arts and Letters - David H. Stevens Oral History - Supplementary Material (III), 1975; Folder 3 of 4 (Box 21, Folder 196)
  - Wisconsin Academy of Sciences, Arts and Letters - David H. Stevens Oral History - Supplementary Material (IV), 1970, 1975-1976; Folder 4 of 4 (Box 22, Folder 197)
  - Women in American History, 1971-May 1972 (Box 22, Folder 198)
  - Women in American History, June-October 1972 (Box 22, Folder 199)
  - Yale University - American Music Oral History, 1970-1971 (Box 22, Folder 200)
  - Yale University - American Music Oral History, 1972-1973 (Box 22, Folder 201)
  - Yale University - American Music Oral History, 1974-1976 (Box 22, Folder 202)
  - Yale University - American Music Oral History - Evaluation, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 203)
  - Yale University - American Music Oral History - Supplementary Material (I), 1970; Folder 1 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 204)
  - Yale University - American Music Oral History - Supplementary Material (II), 1970-1977; Folder 2 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 205)
  - Yale University - Garvin, Philip, 1970-1975 (Box 22, Folder 206)
  - Yale University - Garvin, Philip, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 207)
- Fellowships for American Playwrights/Playwrights-in-Residence Program, 1968-1997; 272; 44 Box(es)
  In 1970, the Rockefeller Foundation launched a program of fellowships for American playwrights, which centered on residencies in selected theaters. The goals of the program were to support playwrights of demonstrated talent at critical middle stages of their careers, and to support innovative regional theaters and younger playwrights throughout the United States. There were two levels of grant awards. The first granted a fellowship to the playwright, who then chose an association with a theater at which to serve a six-week residency. The second level selected ten regional theaters to receive grants that allowed them to name a local playwright to a similar six-week residency. In both cases, the theaters received funds to help defray production costs associated with the residency.
  There were a number of unusual aspects to the playwright-in-residence program. For one, playwrights could not apply for these fellowships. The Foundation solicited nominations from theaters and directors from around the country, and then selected eight playwrights from among the nominees. For another, apart from the six-week residency, the money arrived with no strings attached. There was no requirement that something be written or something produced. The Rockefeller Foundation was investing in the future; as one officer explained, it was not looking to get something for its money.